<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1312.6199v4</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2014-02-19T16:33:14Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2013-12-21T03:36:08Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Intriguing properties of neural networks</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Deep neural networks are highly expressive models that have recently achieved
state of the art performance on speech and visual recognition tasks. While
their expressiveness is the reason they succeed, it also causes them to learn
uninterpretable solutions that could have counter-intuitive properties. In this
paper we report two such properties.
  First, we find that there is no distinction between individual high level
units and random linear combinations of high level units, according to various
methods of unit analysis. It suggests that it is the space, rather than the
individual units, that contains of the semantic information in the high layers
of neural networks.
  Second, we find that deep neural networks learn input-output mappings that
are fairly discontinuous to a significant extend. We can cause the network to
misclassify an image by applying a certain imperceptible perturbation, which is
found by maximizing the network's prediction error. In addition, the specific
nature of these perturbations is not a random artifact of learning: the same
perturbation can cause a different network, that was trained on a different
subset of the dataset, to misclassify the same input.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Christian Szegedy</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wojciech Zaremba</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ilya Sutskever</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Joan Bruna</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Dumitru Erhan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ian Goodfellow</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rob Fergus</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1312.6199v4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1312.6199v4" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
