<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.3711v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2012-11-14T19:25:21Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2012-11-14T19:25:21Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Sequence Transduction with Recurrent Neural Networks</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Many machine learning tasks can be expressed as the transformation---or
\emph{transduction}---of input sequences into output sequences: speech
recognition, machine translation, protein secondary structure prediction and
text-to-speech to name but a few. One of the key challenges in sequence
transduction is learning to represent both the input and output sequences in a
way that is invariant to sequential distortions such as shrinking, stretching
and translating. Recurrent neural networks (RNNs) are a powerful sequence
learning architecture that has proven capable of learning such representations.
However RNNs traditionally require a pre-defined alignment between the input
and output sequences to perform transduction. This is a severe limitation since
\emph{finding} the alignment is the most difficult aspect of many sequence
transduction problems. Indeed, even determining the length of the output
sequence is often challenging. This paper introduces an end-to-end,
probabilistic sequence transduction system, based entirely on RNNs, that is in
principle able to transform any input sequence into any finite, discrete output
sequence. Experimental results for phoneme recognition are provided on the
TIMIT speech corpus.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Alex Graves</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>First published in the International Conference of Machine Learning
  (ICML) 2012 Workshop on Representation Learning</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1211.3711v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1211.3711v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
