<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1406.6312v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2014-11-19T00:18:06Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2014-06-24T17:10:29Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Scalable Topical Phrase Mining from Text Corpora</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  While most topic modeling algorithms model text corpora with unigrams, human
interpretation often relies on inherent grouping of terms into phrases. As
such, we consider the problem of discovering topical phrases of mixed lengths.
Existing work either performs post processing to the inference results of
unigram-based topic models, or utilizes complex n-gram-discovery topic models.
These methods generally produce low-quality topical phrases or suffer from poor
scalability on even moderately-sized datasets. We propose a different approach
that is both computationally efficient and effective. Our solution combines a
novel phrase mining framework to segment a document into single and multi-word
phrases, and a new topic model that operates on the induced document partition.
Our approach discovers high quality topical phrases with negligible extra cost
to the bag-of-words topic model in a variety of datasets including research
publication titles, abstracts, reviews, and news articles.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ahmed El-Kishky</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yanglei Song</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chi Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Clare Voss</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiawei Han</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:journal_ref>Proceedings of the VLDB Endowment, Vol. 8(3), pp. 305 - 316, 2014</ns1:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1406.6312v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1406.6312v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
