<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1412.6596v3</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2015-04-15T19:48:37Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2014-12-20T04:11:33Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Training Deep Neural Networks on Noisy Labels with Bootstrapping</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Current state-of-the-art deep learning systems for visual object recognition
and detection use purely supervised training with regularization such as
dropout to avoid overfitting. The performance depends critically on the amount
of labeled examples, and in current practice the labels are assumed to be
unambiguous and accurate. However, this assumption often does not hold; e.g. in
recognition, class labels may be missing; in detection, objects in the image
may not be localized; and in general, the labeling may be subjective. In this
work we propose a generic way to handle noisy and incomplete labeling by
augmenting the prediction objective with a notion of consistency. We consider a
prediction consistent if the same prediction is made given similar percepts,
where the notion of similarity is between deep network features computed from
the input data. In experiments we demonstrate that our approach yields
substantial robustness to label noise on several datasets. On MNIST handwritten
digits, we show that our model is robust to label corruption. On the Toronto
Face Database, we show that our model handles well the case of subjective
labels in emotion recognition, achieving state-of-the- art results, and can
also benefit from unlabeled face images with no modification to our method. On
the ILSVRC2014 detection challenge data, we show that our approach extends to
very deep networks, high resolution images and structured outputs, and results
in improved scalable detection.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Scott Reed</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Honglak Lee</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Dragomir Anguelov</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Christian Szegedy</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Dumitru Erhan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Andrew Rabinovich</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1412.6596v3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1412.6596v3" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
