<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1511.04854v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2015-11-16T07:55:37Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2015-11-16T07:55:37Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>A Survey of Heterogeneous Information Network Analysis</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Most real systems consist of a large number of interacting, multi-typed
components, while most contemporary researches model them as homogeneous
networks, without distinguishing different types of objects and links in the
networks. Recently, more and more researchers begin to consider these
interconnected, multi-typed data as heterogeneous information networks, and
develop structural analysis approaches by leveraging the rich semantic meaning
of structural types of objects and links in the networks. Compared to widely
studied homogeneous network, the heterogeneous information network contains
richer structure and semantic information, which provides plenty of
opportunities as well as a lot of challenges for data mining. In this paper, we
provide a survey of heterogeneous information network analysis. We will
introduce basic concepts of heterogeneous information network analysis, examine
its developments on different data mining tasks, discuss some advanced topics,
and point out some future research directions.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chuan Shi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yitong Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiawei Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yizhou Sun</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Philip S. Yu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>45 pages, 12 figures</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1511.04854v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1511.04854v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="physics.soc-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
