<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1506.03134v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2017-01-02T10:25:29Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2015-06-09T23:38:16Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Pointer Networks</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We introduce a new neural architecture to learn the conditional probability
of an output sequence with elements that are discrete tokens corresponding to
positions in an input sequence. Such problems cannot be trivially addressed by
existent approaches such as sequence-to-sequence and Neural Turing Machines,
because the number of target classes in each step of the output depends on the
length of the input, which is variable. Problems such as sorting variable sized
sequences, and various combinatorial optimization problems belong to this
class. Our model solves the problem of variable size output dictionaries using
a recently proposed mechanism of neural attention. It differs from the previous
attention attempts in that, instead of using attention to blend hidden units of
an encoder to a context vector at each decoder step, it uses attention as a
pointer to select a member of the input sequence as the output. We call this
architecture a Pointer Net (Ptr-Net). We show Ptr-Nets can be used to learn
approximate solutions to three challenging geometric problems -- finding planar
convex hulls, computing Delaunay triangulations, and the planar Travelling
Salesman Problem -- using training examples alone. Ptr-Nets not only improve
over sequence-to-sequence with input attention, but also allow us to generalize
to variable size output dictionaries. We show that the learnt models generalize
beyond the maximum lengths they were trained on. We hope our results on these
tasks will encourage a broader exploration of neural learning for discrete
problems.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Oriol Vinyals</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Meire Fortunato</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Navdeep Jaitly</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1506.03134v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1506.03134v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.NE" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
