<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1511.06709v4</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2016-06-03T15:09:54Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2015-11-20T17:58:37Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Improving Neural Machine Translation Models with Monolingual Data</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Neural Machine Translation (NMT) has obtained state-of-the art performance
for several language pairs, while only using parallel data for training.
Target-side monolingual data plays an important role in boosting fluency for
phrase-based statistical machine translation, and we investigate the use of
monolingual data for NMT. In contrast to previous work, which combines NMT
models with separately trained language models, we note that encoder-decoder
NMT architectures already have the capacity to learn the same information as a
language model, and we explore strategies to train with monolingual data
without changing the neural network architecture. By pairing monolingual
training data with an automatic back-translation, we can treat it as additional
parallel training data, and we obtain substantial improvements on the WMT 15
task English&lt;-&gt;German (+2.8-3.7 BLEU), and for the low-resourced IWSLT 14 task
Turkish-&gt;English (+2.1-3.4 BLEU), obtaining new state-of-the-art results. We
also show that fine-tuning on in-domain monolingual and parallel data gives
substantial improvements for the IWSLT 15 task English-&gt;German.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Rico Sennrich</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Barry Haddow</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Alexandra Birch</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>accepted to ACL 2016; new section on effect of back-translation
  quality</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1511.06709v4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1511.06709v4" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
