<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1704.07709v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2017-04-25T14:19:26Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2017-04-25T14:19:26Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Inception Recurrent Convolutional Neural Network for Object Recognition</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Deep convolutional neural networks (DCNNs) are an influential tool for
solving various problems in the machine learning and computer vision fields. In
this paper, we introduce a new deep learning model called an Inception-
Recurrent Convolutional Neural Network (IRCNN), which utilizes the power of an
inception network combined with recurrent layers in DCNN architecture. We have
empirically evaluated the recognition performance of the proposed IRCNN model
using different benchmark datasets such as MNIST, CIFAR-10, CIFAR- 100, and
SVHN. Experimental results show similar or higher recognition accuracy when
compared to most of the popular DCNNs including the RCNN. Furthermore, we have
investigated IRCNN performance against equivalent Inception Networks and
Inception-Residual Networks using the CIFAR-100 dataset. We report about 3.5%,
3.47% and 2.54% improvement in classification accuracy when compared to the
RCNN, equivalent Inception Networks, and Inception- Residual Networks on the
augmented CIFAR- 100 dataset respectively.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Md Zahangir Alom</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mahmudul Hasan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chris Yakopcic</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tarek M. Taha</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>11 pages, 10 figures, 2 tables</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1704.07709v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1704.07709v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
