<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1612.00584v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2017-03-09T12:36:26Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2016-12-02T07:45:40Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Alleviating Overfitting for Polysemous Words for Word Representation
  Estimation Using Lexicons</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Though there are some works on improving distributed word representations
using lexicons, the improper overfitting of the words that have multiple
meanings is a remaining issue deteriorating the learning when lexicons are
used, which needs to be solved. An alternative method is to allocate a vector
per sense instead of a vector per word. However, the word representations
estimated in the former way are not as easy to use as the latter one. Our
previous work uses a probabilistic method to alleviate the overfitting, but it
is not robust with a small corpus. In this paper, we propose a new neural
network to estimate distributed word representations using a lexicon and a
corpus. We add a lexicon layer in the continuous bag-of-words model and a
threshold node after the output of the lexicon layer. The threshold rejects the
unreliable outputs of the lexicon layer that are less likely to be the same
with their inputs. In this way, it alleviates the overfitting of the polysemous
words. The proposed neural network can be trained using negative sampling,
which maximizing the log probabilities of target words given the context words,
by distinguishing the target words from random noises. We compare the proposed
neural network with the continuous bag-of-words model, the other works
improving it, and the previous works estimating distributed word
representations using both a lexicon and a corpus. The experimental results
show that the proposed neural network is more efficient and balanced for both
semantic tasks and syntactic tasks than the previous works, and robust to the
size of the corpus.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yuanzhi Ke</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Masafumi Hagiwara</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>Accepted by IEEE IJCNN 2017. Copyright transferred to IEEE</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1612.00584v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1612.00584v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
