<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1708.05031v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2017-08-26T01:37:09Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2017-08-16T18:30:09Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Neural Collaborative Filtering</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In recent years, deep neural networks have yielded immense success on speech
recognition, computer vision and natural language processing. However, the
exploration of deep neural networks on recommender systems has received
relatively less scrutiny. In this work, we strive to develop techniques based
on neural networks to tackle the key problem in recommendation -- collaborative
filtering -- on the basis of implicit feedback. Although some recent work has
employed deep learning for recommendation, they primarily used it to model
auxiliary information, such as textual descriptions of items and acoustic
features of musics. When it comes to model the key factor in collaborative
filtering -- the interaction between user and item features, they still
resorted to matrix factorization and applied an inner product on the latent
features of users and items. By replacing the inner product with a neural
architecture that can learn an arbitrary function from data, we present a
general framework named NCF, short for Neural network-based Collaborative
Filtering. NCF is generic and can express and generalize matrix factorization
under its framework. To supercharge NCF modelling with non-linearities, we
propose to leverage a multi-layer perceptron to learn the user-item interaction
function. Extensive experiments on two real-world datasets show significant
improvements of our proposed NCF framework over the state-of-the-art methods.
Empirical evidence shows that using deeper layers of neural networks offers
better recommendation performance.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiangnan He</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Lizi Liao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Hanwang Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Liqiang Nie</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xia Hu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Tat-Seng Chua</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>10 pages, 7 figures</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1708.05031v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1708.05031v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
