<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1704.08847v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2017-05-02T01:11:21Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2017-04-28T08:43:55Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Parseval Networks: Improving Robustness to Adversarial Examples</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  We introduce Parseval networks, a form of deep neural networks in which the
Lipschitz constant of linear, convolutional and aggregation layers is
constrained to be smaller than 1. Parseval networks are empirically and
theoretically motivated by an analysis of the robustness of the predictions
made by deep neural networks when their input is subject to an adversarial
perturbation. The most important feature of Parseval networks is to maintain
weight matrices of linear and convolutional layers to be (approximately)
Parseval tight frames, which are extensions of orthogonal matrices to
non-square matrices. We describe how these constraints can be maintained
efficiently during SGD. We show that Parseval networks match the
state-of-the-art in terms of accuracy on CIFAR-10/100 and Street View House
Numbers (SVHN) while being more robust than their vanilla counterpart against
adversarial examples. Incidentally, Parseval networks also tend to train faster
and make a better usage of the full capacity of the networks.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Moustapha Cisse</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Piotr Bojanowski</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Edouard Grave</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Yann Dauphin</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Nicolas Usunier</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>submitted</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1704.08847v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1704.08847v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
