<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1711.06350v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2017-11-16T23:18:03Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2017-11-16T23:18:03Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Towards Deep Learning Models for Psychological State Prediction using
  Smartphone Data: Challenges and Opportunities</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  There is an increasing interest in exploiting mobile sensing technologies and
machine learning techniques for mental health monitoring and intervention.
Researchers have effectively used contextual information, such as mobility,
communication and mobile phone usage patterns for quantifying individuals' mood
and wellbeing. In this paper, we investigate the effectiveness of neural
network models for predicting users' level of stress by using the location
information collected by smartphones. We characterize the mobility patterns of
individuals using the GPS metrics presented in the literature and employ these
metrics as input to the network. We evaluate our approach on the open-source
StudentLife dataset. Moreover, we discuss the challenges and trade-offs
involved in building machine learning models for digital mental health and
highlight potential future work in this direction.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Gatis Mikelsons</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Matthew Smith</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Abhinav Mehrotra</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Mirco Musolesi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>6 pages, 2 figures, In Proceedings of the NIPS Workshop on Machine
  Learning for Healthcare 2017 (ML4H 2017). Colocated with NIPS 2017</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1711.06350v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1711.06350v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.AI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
