<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1803.09803v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2018-04-23T15:08:51Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2018-03-26T19:25:02Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Generating Talking Face Landmarks from Speech</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  The presence of a corresponding talking face has been shown to significantly
improve speech intelligibility in noisy conditions and for hearing impaired
population. In this paper, we present a system that can generate landmark
points of a talking face from an acoustic speech in real time. The system uses
a long short-term memory (LSTM) network and is trained on frontal videos of 27
different speakers with automatically extracted face landmarks. After training,
it can produce talking face landmarks from the acoustic speech of unseen
speakers and utterances. The training phase contains three key steps. We first
transform landmarks of the first video frame to pin the two eye points into two
predefined locations and apply the same transformation on all of the following
video frames. We then remove the identity information by transforming the
landmarks into a mean face shape across the entire training dataset. Finally,
we train an LSTM network that takes the first- and second-order temporal
differences of the log-mel spectrogram as input to predict face landmarks in
each frame. We evaluate our system using the mean-squared error (MSE) loss of
landmarks of lips between predicted and ground-truth landmarks as well as their
first- and second-order temporal differences. We further evaluate our system by
conducting subjective tests, where the subjects try to distinguish the real and
fake videos of talking face landmarks. Both tests show promising results.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sefik Emre Eskimez</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ross K Maddox</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chenliang Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Zhiyao Duan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>To Appear in LVA ICA 2018. Please see the following link:
  http://www2.ece.rochester.edu/projects/air/projects/talkingface.html</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1803.09803v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1803.09803v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
