<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1803.06253v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2018-03-16T14:48:58Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2018-03-16T14:48:58Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Land cover mapping at very high resolution with rotation equivariant
  CNNs: towards small yet accurate models</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In remote sensing images, the absolute orientation of objects is arbitrary.
Depending on an object's orientation and on a sensor's flight path, objects of
the same semantic class can be observed in different orientations in the same
image. Equivariance to rotation, in this context understood as responding with
a rotated semantic label map when subject to a rotation of the input image, is
therefore a very desirable feature, in particular for high capacity models,
such as Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs). If rotation equivariance is
encoded in the network, the model is confronted with a simpler task and does
not need to learn specific (and redundant) weights to address rotated versions
of the same object class. In this work we propose a CNN architecture called
Rotation Equivariant Vector Field Network (RotEqNet) to encode rotation
equivariance in the network itself. By using rotating convolutions as building
blocks and passing only the the values corresponding to the maximally
activating orientation throughout the network in the form of orientation
encoding vector fields, RotEqNet treats rotated versions of the same object
with the same filter bank and therefore achieves state-of-the-art performances
even when using very small architectures trained from scratch. We test RotEqNet
in two challenging sub-decimeter resolution semantic labeling problems, and
show that we can perform better than a standard CNN while requiring one order
of magnitude less parameters.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Diego Marcos</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Michele Volpi</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Benjamin Kellenberger</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Devis Tuia</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:doi>10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2018.01.021</ns1:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2018.01.021" rel="related" />
    <ns1:journal_ref>ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, 2018</ns1:journal_ref>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1803.06253v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1803.06253v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
