<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1805.09112v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2018-06-28T17:20:43Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2018-05-23T13:08:07Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Hyperbolic Neural Networks</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Hyperbolic spaces have recently gained momentum in the context of machine
learning due to their high capacity and tree-likeliness properties. However,
the representational power of hyperbolic geometry is not yet on par with
Euclidean geometry, mostly because of the absence of corresponding hyperbolic
neural network layers. This makes it hard to use hyperbolic embeddings in
downstream tasks. Here, we bridge this gap in a principled manner by combining
the formalism of M\"obius gyrovector spaces with the Riemannian geometry of the
Poincar\'e model of hyperbolic spaces. As a result, we derive hyperbolic
versions of important deep learning tools: multinomial logistic regression,
feed-forward and recurrent neural networks such as gated recurrent units. This
allows to embed sequential data and perform classification in the hyperbolic
space. Empirically, we show that, even if hyperbolic optimization tools are
limited, hyperbolic sentence embeddings either outperform or are on par with
their Euclidean variants on textual entailment and noisy-prefix recognition
tasks.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Octavian-Eugen Ganea</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Gary B&#233;cigneul</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Thomas Hofmann</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1805.09112v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1805.09112v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
