<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1803.03467v4</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2018-08-25T05:52:08Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2018-03-09T11:12:01Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>RippleNet: Propagating User Preferences on the Knowledge Graph for
  Recommender Systems</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  To address the sparsity and cold start problem of collaborative filtering,
researchers usually make use of side information, such as social networks or
item attributes, to improve recommendation performance. This paper considers
the knowledge graph as the source of side information. To address the
limitations of existing embedding-based and path-based methods for
knowledge-graph-aware recommendation, we propose Ripple Network, an end-to-end
framework that naturally incorporates the knowledge graph into recommender
systems. Similar to actual ripples propagating on the surface of water, Ripple
Network stimulates the propagation of user preferences over the set of
knowledge entities by automatically and iteratively extending a user's
potential interests along links in the knowledge graph. The multiple "ripples"
activated by a user's historically clicked items are thus superposed to form
the preference distribution of the user with respect to a candidate item, which
could be used for predicting the final clicking probability. Through extensive
experiments on real-world datasets, we demonstrate that Ripple Network achieves
substantial gains in a variety of scenarios, including movie, book and news
recommendation, over several state-of-the-art baselines.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Hongwei Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Fuzheng Zhang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jialin Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Miao Zhao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wenjie Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xing Xie</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Minyi Guo</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:doi>10.1145/3269206.3271739</ns1:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3269206.3271739" rel="related" />
    <ns1:comment>CIKM 2018</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1803.03467v4" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1803.03467v4" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
