<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1811.01057v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2018-11-02T19:08:04Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2018-11-02T19:08:04Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Semidefinite relaxations for certifying robustness to adversarial
  examples</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Despite their impressive performance on diverse tasks, neural networks fail
catastrophically in the presence of adversarial inputs---imperceptibly but
adversarially perturbed versions of natural inputs. We have witnessed an arms
race between defenders who attempt to train robust networks and attackers who
try to construct adversarial examples. One promise of ending the arms race is
developing certified defenses, ones which are provably robust against all
attackers in some family. These certified defenses are based on convex
relaxations which construct an upper bound on the worst case loss over all
attackers in the family. Previous relaxations are loose on networks that are
not trained against the respective relaxation. In this paper, we propose a new
semidefinite relaxation for certifying robustness that applies to arbitrary
ReLU networks. We show that our proposed relaxation is tighter than previous
relaxations and produces meaningful robustness guarantees on three different
"foreign networks" whose training objectives are agnostic to our proposed
relaxation.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Aditi Raghunathan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jacob Steinhardt</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Percy Liang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>To appear at NIPS 2018</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1811.01057v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1811.01057v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
