<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1812.05161v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2018-12-12T21:26:43Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2018-12-12T21:26:43Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Estimating Position Bias without Intrusive Interventions</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Presentation bias is one of the key challenges when learning from implicit
feedback in search engines, as it confounds the relevance signal. While it was
recently shown how counterfactual learning-to-rank (LTR) approaches
\cite{Joachims/etal/17a} can provably overcome presentation bias when
observation propensities are known, it remains to show how to effectively
estimate these propensities. In this paper, we propose the first method for
producing consistent propensity estimates without manual relevance judgments,
disruptive interventions, or restrictive relevance modeling assumptions. First,
we show how to harvest a specific type of intervention data from historic
feedback logs of multiple different ranking functions, and show that this data
is sufficient for consistent propensity estimation in the position-based model.
Second, we propose a new extremum estimator that makes effective use of this
data. In an empirical evaluation, we find that the new estimator provides
superior propensity estimates in two real-world systems -- Arxiv Full-text
Search and Google Drive Search. Beyond these two points, we find that the
method is robust to a wide range of settings in simulation studies.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Aman Agarwal</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Ivan Zaitsev</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xuanhui Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Cheng Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Marc Najork</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Thorsten Joachims</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:doi>10.1145/3289600.3291017</ns1:doi>
    <ns0:link title="doi" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3289600.3291017" rel="related" />
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1812.05161v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1812.05161v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.IR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
