<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1903.06586v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2019-03-18T03:08:24Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2019-03-15T15:04:22Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Selective Kernel Networks</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  In standard Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs), the receptive fields of
artificial neurons in each layer are designed to share the same size. It is
well-known in the neuroscience community that the receptive field size of
visual cortical neurons are modulated by the stimulus, which has been rarely
considered in constructing CNNs. We propose a dynamic selection mechanism in
CNNs that allows each neuron to adaptively adjust its receptive field size
based on multiple scales of input information. A building block called
Selective Kernel (SK) unit is designed, in which multiple branches with
different kernel sizes are fused using softmax attention that is guided by the
information in these branches. Different attentions on these branches yield
different sizes of the effective receptive fields of neurons in the fusion
layer. Multiple SK units are stacked to a deep network termed Selective Kernel
Networks (SKNets). On the ImageNet and CIFAR benchmarks, we empirically show
that SKNet outperforms the existing state-of-the-art architectures with lower
model complexity. Detailed analyses show that the neurons in SKNet can capture
target objects with different scales, which verifies the capability of neurons
for adaptively adjusting their receptive field sizes according to the input.
The code and models are available at https://github.com/implus/SKNet.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiang Li</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Wenhai Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Xiaolin Hu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jian Yang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>CVPR 2019</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1903.06586v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1903.06586v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
