<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1905.11006v2</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2019-10-28T07:52:19Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2019-05-27T07:08:12Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Levenshtein Transformer</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Modern neural sequence generation models are built to either generate tokens
step-by-step from scratch or (iteratively) modify a sequence of tokens bounded
by a fixed length. In this work, we develop Levenshtein Transformer, a new
partially autoregressive model devised for more flexible and amenable sequence
generation. Unlike previous approaches, the atomic operations of our model are
insertion and deletion. The combination of them facilitates not only generation
but also sequence refinement allowing dynamic length changes. We also propose a
set of new training techniques dedicated at them, effectively exploiting one as
the other's learning signal thanks to their complementary nature. Experiments
applying the proposed model achieve comparable performance but much-improved
efficiency on both generation (e.g. machine translation, text summarization)
and refinement tasks (e.g. automatic post-editing). We further confirm the
flexibility of our model by showing a Levenshtein Transformer trained by
machine translation can straightforwardly be used for automatic post-editing.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jiatao Gu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Changhan Wang</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Jake Zhao</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns1:comment>17 pages (6 pages appendix). Camera ready, accepted by NeurIPS 2019</ns1:comment>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1905.11006v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1905.11006v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.CL" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
