<ns0:entry xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">
    <ns0:id>http://arxiv.org/abs/2002.07962v1</ns0:id>
    <ns0:updated>2020-02-19T02:05:37Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:published>2020-02-19T02:05:37Z</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title>Inductive Representation Learning on Temporal Graphs</ns0:title>
    <ns0:summary>  Inductive representation learning on temporal graphs is an important step
toward salable machine learning on real-world dynamic networks. The evolving
nature of temporal dynamic graphs requires handling new nodes as well as
capturing temporal patterns. The node embeddings, which are now functions of
time, should represent both the static node features and the evolving
topological structures. Moreover, node and topological features can be temporal
as well, whose patterns the node embeddings should also capture. We propose the
temporal graph attention (TGAT) layer to efficiently aggregate
temporal-topological neighborhood features as well as to learn the time-feature
interactions. For TGAT, we use the self-attention mechanism as building block
and develop a novel functional time encoding technique based on the classical
Bochner's theorem from harmonic analysis. By stacking TGAT layers, the network
recognizes the node embeddings as functions of time and is able to inductively
infer embeddings for both new and observed nodes as the graph evolves. The
proposed approach handles both node classification and link prediction task,
and can be naturally extended to include the temporal edge features. We
evaluate our method with transductive and inductive tasks under temporal
settings with two benchmark and one industrial dataset. Our TGAT model compares
favorably to state-of-the-art baselines as well as the previous temporal graph
embedding approaches.
</ns0:summary>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Da Xu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Chuanwei Ruan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Evren Korpeoglu</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Sushant Kumar</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:author>
      <ns0:name>Kannan Achan</ns0:name>
    </ns0:author>
    <ns0:link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/2002.07962v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/2002.07962v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf" />
    <ns1:primary_category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="cs.LG" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
    <ns0:category term="stat.ML" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" />
  </ns0:entry>
